<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gary Larson</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gary Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Gary Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got LaTeX working with Hugo and blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-got-latex-working-with-hugo-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-got-latex-working-with-hugo-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Solution 0 of 3 First of all, if you need LaTeX but don’t need any R code, just write the post in .md. Then you can use full-line equations like $$x=5$$ to get \[x=5\]
And the typical inline $x=5$ gives you \(x=5\).
 Solution 1 of 3 NOTE: This solution for getting LaTeX to work via MathJax requires the blog post to be in .Rmd format. It doesn’t work in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Produce a Python blog post with figures</title>
      <link>/post/produce-a-python-blog-post-with-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/produce-a-python-blog-post-with-figures/</guid>
      <description>To create a Hugo blog post with Python code and figures, I export an ipython notebook as a .md file. The result is a .zip file containing the .md file and images for the figures. A little modification is needed to get these files just right so that when Hugo builds my website, the post is ready to go with no blank figures. After exporting the jupyter / ipython notebook as .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Python Data Science Handbook</title>
      <link>/post/notes-on-python-data-science-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/notes-on-python-data-science-handbook/</guid>
      <description>This notebook is on my local filesystem under ~/github/learning-python/notes-PDSH.ipynb and contains notes I made while studying topics from the Python Data Science Handbook by Jake Vanderplas. His Github repo of the book is here. I forked the repo, and that clone is located on my local filesystem at
~/github/jakevdp_PythonDataScienceHandbook  Chapter 3: Data Manipulation with Pandas (p. 97) Introducing Pandas objects (p. 98) The Pandas Index object (p. 105) Index objects are immutable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression in Python</title>
      <link>/post/regression-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/regression-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Linear and Polynomial Regression Here&amp;rsquo;s some cool initial code from page 378 (under &amp;ldquo;Derived Features&amp;rdquo; in the section on Feature Engineering) in the Python Data Science Handbook (PDSH). This code will allow me to quickly fit a linear and polynomial regression to very simple data. My comments are marked something like ### GJL::
% matplotlib inline import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt x = np.array([1,2,3,4,5]) y = np.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: single underscores vs. double underscores</title>
      <link>/post/single-underscore-vs-double-underscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/single-underscore-vs-double-underscore/</guid>
      <description>This Youtube video is a really great 6 minute demonstration of the distinction between _ and __. I&amp;rsquo;ll embed the linked video at the end of this post. One of the top comments on that video says
 For C++ people, foo is public, _bar is protected, and __baz is private.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple class, with an initializer implemented, including the three variables foo, _bar, and __baz.
class Test: def __init__(self): self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax highlighting for a Hugo data science blog</title>
      <link>/post/syntax-highlighting-for-a-hugo-data-science-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/syntax-highlighting-for-a-hugo-data-science-blog/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: I believe this requires the post to be in .Rmarkdown format, and that an .Rmd post will not have the syntax highlighting.
This post explains how I set up my Hugo blog (with the Whiteplain theme) to get the type of syntax highlighting I want for data science / statistics purposes. I relied heavily on this post from Amber Thomas. Thanks a lot Amber! If I were you, I&amp;rsquo;d probably use Amber&amp;rsquo;s more thorough post as a guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with runnable Python in Rmarkdown files</title>
      <link>/post/blogging-with-runnable-python-in-rmarkdown-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blogging-with-runnable-python-in-rmarkdown-files/</guid>
      <description>I wondered if I could blog with runnable Python code chunks if I&amp;rsquo;m creating my Hugo content with .Rmarkdown files. It looks like I can with the reticulate package; see the vignette here.
install.packages(&#39;reticulate&#39;, repos=&amp;quot;https://cloud.r-project.org&amp;quot;) library(reticulate)  I believe this allows you to actually run Python. Alternatively, if you just want to display Python code, just use a code fence, i.e. the Github-style code block that&amp;rsquo;s 3 backticks, new line, code, then three closing backticks on a new line, like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takeover of the Allen Building</title>
      <link>/post/takeover-of-the-allen-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/takeover-of-the-allen-building/</guid>
      <description>Being a subscriber on Flickr to Duke University Archive&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Duke Yearlook&amp;rdquo; photostream, some pretty cool stuff comes up on my home page at Flickr. Today I learned about the 1969 takeover of the Allen Building, which is today (and presumably was then, too) an epicenter for the University administration. Apparently black students on campus were tired of the University dragging their feet &amp;ndash; tired of going through the so-called &amp;ldquo;proper channels&amp;rdquo; for over 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Draper’s personal statement</title>
      <link>/post/david-draper-s-personal-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/david-draper-s-personal-statement/</guid>
      <description>I was browsing around tonight on the topic of Bayesian model averaging. I stumbled on David Draper&amp;rsquo;s website where he posts a document called &amp;ldquo;Personal Statement&amp;rdquo; which he wrote in support of him getting a &amp;ldquo;merit increase&amp;rdquo; (i.e. a raise). Here&amp;rsquo;s the link, and in case the link dies, here&amp;rsquo;s the document.
Section 3 is great reading. He first gives a clear summary of frequentist vs. Bayesian stats, then goes on to give a little of his philosophy and biography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective Bayes - Day 1</title>
      <link>/post/objective-bayes-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/objective-bayes-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a course by Jim Berger on Objective Bayesian Analysis. It begins with the motivation and history behind 250 years of objective Bayesian analysis, and today he shared an interesting tidbit.
It won&amp;rsquo;t be published publicly on my blog (yet) because Jim mentioned it could be an interesting reveal at Duke Statistical Science&amp;rsquo;s upcoming conference celebrating the 250 year anniversary of the publishing of Bayes&amp;rsquo; Theorem.
Statistician / statistics historian Stephen Stigler was wondering why Bayes was interested in the problem which led to the 1763 paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boxes around aligned equations in LaTeX</title>
      <link>/post/boxes-around-aligned-equations-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/boxes-around-aligned-equations-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>Example of how to get boxes around equations in the aligned environment in LaTeX:
\begin{equation} \boxed{ \begin{aligned} x^2 + 1 &amp;amp;= 2 \\ x^4 + 1 &amp;amp;= 3 \end{aligned} } \end{equation} I’d like to show the result, but at time of writing I realize I don’t have my workflow set up to properly render LaTeX equations in the final Hugo post. Here’s what I get instead: (if this looks right, then I must have fixed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test new post via add-in menu</title>
      <link>/post/test-new-post-via-add-in-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/test-new-post-via-add-in-menu/</guid>
      <description>To write a new post (like this one) using blogdown in RStudio, just click &amp;ldquo;Addins&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;New Post&amp;rdquo; near the top of the RStudio window.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some junk R code. In the chunk options, just set eval=FALSE.
plot(x)  I should get used to writing (R) markdown pretty quickly, after translating a few of my plot posts.
Just for fun, here&amp;rsquo;s a plot.
plot(x &amp;lt;- seq(-10,10,length.out=100), sin(x), type=&#39;l&#39;, xlab=&#39;x&#39;, ylab=&#39;sin(x)&#39;)  Syntax highlighting At time of writing, I&amp;rsquo;m still having problems with syntax highlighting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>